French narrator:
Ah, Avocondo Acres,
法语旁白：
啊，阿沃孔多英亩，
Bikini Bottom's premier
retirement community.
比基尼泳裤的首屈一指
退休社区。
This is where we find
Harold and Margaret,
这是我们找到的地方
哈罗德和玛格丽特，
the parents of the ocean's
most exceptional
海洋的父母
最特别的
multicellular organism,
多细胞生物，
SpongeBob SquarePants.
海绵宝宝。
Harold, do you smell that?
哈罗德，你闻到了吗？
It smells like something...
闻起来好像有什么东西...
rotting.
腐烂。
It's begun.
We better run.
开始了。
我们最好跑。
Oh!
哦！
Oh...
哦...
I tell people the rub
their homes with lemon juice
我告诉人们困难
他们家有柠檬汁
and wrap it in plastic.
并用塑料包裹它。
But do they listen?
但他们听吗？
Oh, Harold, what will we do?
哦，哈罗德，我们该怎么办？
Well, we'll just
have to grow a new home.
好吧，我们就
必须建造一个新家。
And in the meantime,
与此同时，
We can stay with our son.
我们可以和我们的儿子呆在一起。
Take cover, Gary!
躲起来，加里！
Watch this.
I jump up and down.
注意这个。
我上蹿下跳。
The soda bottles
pop their corks
苏打水瓶
弹出他们的软木塞
and send me careening
dangerously around the room!
让我倾斜
房间周围很危险！
I may not survive.
我可能活不下去了。
Hello?
你好？
Oh, hi, Mom.
Hi, Dad.
哦，嗨，妈妈。
嗨，爸爸。
Your house?
Oh, no.
你家？
哦，不。
Stay with me?
Why, of course you can!
留在我身边？
为什么，当然可以！
Ooh, guess what, Gary.
哦，你猜怎么着，加里。
Mom and Dad are coming over
爸爸妈妈过来了
to stay at our place
留在我们的地方
for the very first time!
第一次！
I just thought of something.
我刚刚想到一件事。
My parents haven't seen me
in a while.
我的父母没有见过我
一会儿。
They'll be expecting
their son to be a little more,
他们会期待
他们的儿子要多一点，
well, adult--
嗯，大人——
grown-up, mature--
长大了、成熟了——
and look at me!
看着我！
And look at this place!
看看这个地方！
It's a filthy mess!
真是一团糟！
Whoa!
哇！
Peek-a-boo.
躲猫猫。
French narrator: Clean.
法国旁白：干净。
Whoa!
哇！
Ah!
啊!
I see you.
我看见你。
French narrator: So clean.
法国旁白：太干净了。
What?
- We gotta stop
什么？
-我们得停下来
meeting like this.
像这样的聚会。
You almost done?
你快完成了吗？
Wee!
威！
Ooh!
Won't this be fun, dear?
哦！
亲爱的，这不是很有趣吗？
I'm looking forward
to hanging out
我很期待
闲逛
with a hip, young urbanite
like our boy.
与一位时髦的年轻都市人
就像我们的男孩。
Oh, yes, dear.
哦，是的，亲爱的。
We can really use an injection
我们真的可以使用注射
of youthful spirit,
充满青春活力，
vitality, and dare I say,
活力，我敢说，
recklessness.
鲁莽。
Huh?
啊？
Hello, Mater, Pater.
你好，母亲，佩特。
This is truly a pleasure.
这实在是一种享受。
- Ooh!
- Won't you entrer?
- 哦！
- 你不想参加吗？
French narrator: One--
法国旁白：一个——
entrée later...
稍后主菜...
-
- So
- 那么
what are we gonna do today?
今天我们要做什么？
I can't wait to hit the town.
我等不及要进城了。
I have taken the liberty
of writing up an agenda
我已经冒昧了
制定议程
of activities
that I know all of us adults
活动数量
我认识我们所有的成年人
will find most stimulating.
会觉得最刺激。
We'll begin
with a leisurely walk
我们将开始
悠闲地散步
about the neighborhood
so we can critique
关于附近
所以我们可以批评
other people's lawns.
别人的草坪。
After that--conversations
about taxes, politics,
之后——对话
关于税收、政治、
and how things aren't nearly
as good as they used to be,
事情并不接近
和以前一样好，
then an early-bird dinner,
然后是早鸟晚餐，
and we'll top it off
with bedtime at 4:00 p.m.
我们会完成它
下午 4:00 就寝
But son, this isn't--
但是儿子，这不是——
Whatever you say, son.
不管你说什么，儿子。
We're your guests.
我们是你的客人。
French narrator:
4:00 in the afternoon.
法语旁白：
下午 4:00。
Some warm milk
一些温牛奶
and the soothing sounds
of disapproval
和舒缓的声音
不赞成的
to whisk you off
to your slumbers.
把你带走
到你的睡眠。
Mm-mm-mm.
You are so grounded.
嗯-嗯-嗯。
你真是太接地气了。
Will you puh-lease
你会租吗
stop that confounded racket?
停止那个混乱的喧闹吗？
Some grown-ups are
有些成年人是
trying to sleep in here!
想睡在这里！
Sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
What?
什么？
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Good night,
my dear gastropod.
晚安，
我亲爱的腹足动物。
Margaret, dear,
玛格丽特，亲爱的，
I'm afraid our son has become,
恐怕我们的儿子变成了
well, a fuddy duddy.
好吧，一个古板的家伙。
Pardon my language.
请原谅我的语言。
Well,
I was gonna say "bummer,
嗯，
我本来想说“真糟糕，
a downer, and a total drag."
令人沮丧，而且完全是一种拖累。”
What do you say we sneak out
and have some fun?
你说我们偷偷溜出去怎么样
玩得开心吗？
Way ahead of you.
远远领先于你。
Wee!
威！
Oh, ah!
哦，啊！
Where have you two been?
你们两个去哪儿了？
It is 8:00 at night.
I was worried sick.
现在是晚上 8:00。
我担心得要命。
We were just having
a little fun.
我们刚刚有
有点有趣。
You're both
acting like children.
你们都是
表现得像个孩子。
And you're acting
like a square.
而你却在演戏
像一个正方形。
I am square,
我是正方形，
and I've already committed
to acting mature,
我已经承诺了
表现得成熟，
whether you like it or not.
不管你喜欢与否。
Okay, Mr. Mature,
好吧，成熟先生，
it's time for you
to have some fun,
你的时间到了
玩得开心，
whether you like it or not.
不管你喜欢与否。
It's Bikini Bottom
这是比基尼泳裤
after dark, baby!
天黑后，宝贝！
It's gonna be wild.
这会很疯狂。
Woot, woot!
呜呜呜！
Ah!
啊!
Go on, son.
继续吧，儿子。
Join her.
- Hmph.
加入她吧。
- 哼。
That is an order, son!
这是命令，儿子！
Oh, okay.
哦好的。
I still got it.
我还是明白了。
Come on, killjoy.
来吧，扫兴。
Don't be such a party pooper.
别成为派对上的扫兴者。
Do it.
做吧。
This is
这是
so childish.
太幼稚了。
What is going--
发生什么事了——
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
Yahoo!
雅虎！
Masked luchador wrestling!
蒙面摔跤手！
How juvenile.
多么少年啊。
Well, I guess
this is all right.
嗯，我猜
没关系。
It shouldn't be too wild,
不应该太狂野
just sitting here, watching.
只是坐在这里，看着。
Uh, we're not here to watch.
呃，我们不是来观看的。
We're here to wrestle.
我们是来摔跤的
It's tag team time!
现在是双打时间！
Los Diablos vs. Madre y Padre!
Los Diablos 对阵 Madre y Padre！
Mommy, Daddy, no!
爸爸妈妈，不！
Owie.
欧维。
Mom, Dad!
妈妈，爸爸！
I'm coming!
我来了！
Uh, Mom?
呃，妈妈？
Dad?
- 'Atta boy, SpongeBob!
爸爸？
- '海绵宝宝，阿塔男孩！
We're rooting for you, kiddo!
我们支持你，孩子！
For our next bout,
对于我们的下一场比赛，
it's El Muerte
vs. Señor Peanuts Bag!
这是死亡之神
对阵先生花生袋！
Oh, wait, what?
哦，等等，什么？
Mommy, Daddy!
妈妈、爸爸！
No más!
不可以！
Yay!
Whoa!
耶！
哇！
Now, wasn't that fun?
现在，这不是很有趣吗？
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Where'd that peanut bag guy go?
那个装花生袋的家伙去哪儿了？
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
How 'bout a hot dog?
来个热狗怎么样？
I never even knew there
was a 24-hour roller rink
我从来不知道那里
是一个 24 小时开放的溜冰场
in Bikini Bottom.
穿着比基尼泳裤。
Well, I guess skating slowly
好吧，我想慢慢地滑冰
around and around a roller rink
溜冰场周围又周围
isn't so wild.
没那么狂野。
Rink?
We're skating through town.
溜冰场？
我们正在滑冰穿过城镇。
Ha ha!
哈哈！
- Oh!
- Whoops, excuse me.
- 哦！
- 哎呀，对不起。
Hey!
嘿！
both: Whoa.
- Will you two
两人：哇哦。
- 你们两个愿意吗
please act your age?
请表现出你的年龄？
both: Whoo!
两人：哇！
Please stop!
请停下来！
all: Whoo-hoo!
全体：呼呼！
Will you slow down?
This is crazy!
你会放慢速度吗？
这太疯狂了！
- Whoo!
- Wow!
- 呼！
- 哇！
Please, I beg you...
拜托，我求求你了……
Whoo, whoo.
呼呼。
Ah, whoa, whoa--
啊，哇，哇——
Oh, I just wanted to impress
哦，我只是想给大家留下深刻印象
you two by showing you what
a mature adult I've become.
你们两个向你们展示什么
我已经成为一个成熟的成年人了。
But no, you wanted wild.
但不，你想要狂野。
Okay, fine!
好吧，好吧！
You want wild?
你想要狂野吗？
I'll show you!
我会告诉你！
Wild!
荒野！
Aw, the boy's asleep,
all tuckered out.
噢，男孩睡着了，
全部都被掏空了。
Well, our new avocondo
should be ripe right now.
好吧，我们的新鳄梨
现在应该成熟了。
He'll have to stay with us
他必须和我们呆在一起
until he can
regrow his pineapple.
直到他可以
重新长出他的菠萝。
I wonder when he'll really
grow up and be mature.
我想知道他什么时候才能真正
长大并成熟。
Hopefully not too soon.
Am I right dear?
希望不会太快。
亲爱的，我说得对吗？
Señor Peanuts Bag!
先生花生袋！
I want satisfaction!
我要满足！
Or peanuts...
或者花生...
I'd rather peanuts.
我宁愿吃花生。